<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Solana on</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/docs/solana/</link><description>Recent content in Solana on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://solanaguide.github.io/docs/solana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Solana? How Does It Work?</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/what-is-solana-how-does-it-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/what-is-solana-how-does-it-work/</guid><description>What is Solana (SOL)? Solana is one of the fastest and most functional web-scale projects that leverage the features of programmable blockchain technology to deliver Decentralized Finance (DeFi) solutions. The project’s protocol is:
Safe Censorship-resistant Fast Scalable Flexible It adopts the flexibility of open-source infrastructure to create decentralized apps (DApps) and marketplaces for mass adoption.
Solana&amp;rsquo;s developers state that it is the fastest blockchain globally, supports non-fungible and tokens (NFTs) smart contracts and other decentralized finance platforms.</description></item><item><title>What makes Solana Unique? How Is it different to Ethereum?</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/what-makes-solana-unique-how-is-it-different-to-ethereum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/what-makes-solana-unique-how-is-it-different-to-ethereum/</guid><description>What Makes Solana Unique? When Bitcoin started a few years back, it addressed a seemingly tricky challenge. The problem was that strangers could not make payments for online transactions without third-party payment platforms like PayPal or Visa.
With the introduction of blockchain technology, decentralized transactions became possible, and cryptocurrencies started thriving. This technology is relevant now more than ever, making the market perfect for Solana and related blockchain technology.
However, the challenge with this technology is that it is slower compared to centralized payment networks like credit cards.</description></item><item><title>Solana's History: When Was SOL launched?</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/solanas-history-when-was-sol-launched/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/solanas-history-when-was-sol-launched/</guid><description>When Was Solana Launched? We can trace back the origin of Solana to late 2017, when creator, Anatoly Yakovenko, released a draft whitepaper outlining a novel timekeeping method for distributed systems called Proof of History (PoH). Anatoly formerly worked at Dropbox and Qualcomm and specialized in developing compression techniques and distributed systems.
One of the scalability constraints in blockchains such as Bitcoin and Ethereum is the time needed to achieve an agreement on the sequence of transactions.</description></item><item><title>Where to buy Solana: How to invest on an exchange or DEX</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/where-to-buy-solana-how-to-invest-on-an-exchange-or-dex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/where-to-buy-solana-how-to-invest-on-an-exchange-or-dex/</guid><description>How to Buy or Invest in Solana Solana is a well-known cryptocurrency. Hence, the steps involved in buying it on decentralized exchanges like Uniswap and PancakeSwap are pretty straightforward. Here’s how to buy Solana:
Open an Online Account Unfortunately, the most prominent crypto trading platforms are yet to include Solana on their platforms. We can expect Solana to list on more crypto exchanges in the future since it is such a great initiative.</description></item><item><title>Why Are Solana's 'Gas' Fees For Transactions So Low?</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/why-are-solanas-gas-fees-for-transactions-so-low/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/why-are-solanas-gas-fees-for-transactions-so-low/</guid><description>How Much Are Transaction Fees on Solana vs. Ethereum? Transaction fees in cryptocurrency refer to the charges a user pays when transferring crypto coins from one account to another. Before a transaction can pass or be recorded in the blockchain, it’ll require a certain fee.
Cryptocurrencies generally have three types of transaction fees:
Network fees Wallet fees Crypto exchange fees. Transaction fees vary between coins, depending on two key factors: the time required to generate new blocks on the blockchain and the number of transactions that a single block can handle.</description></item><item><title>Why is Solana's price and popularity going up? Should I invest?'</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/why-is-solanas-price-and-popularity-going-up-should-i-invest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/why-is-solanas-price-and-popularity-going-up-should-i-invest/</guid><description>Why Is Solana Increasing in Popularity and Price? The Solana blockchain network hosts the SOL crypto token in the same manner that the Ethereum blockchain links to the ether token. Recently, SOL gained a massive boost with a market capitalization of over $48 billion.
The SOL cryptocurrency has increased so much that it surpassed Dogecoin, formerly the most famous &amp;ldquo;Joke&amp;rdquo; cryptocurrency. It has become the seventh most significant cryptocurrency by market capitalization.</description></item><item><title>Will Solana Replace Ethereum?</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/will-solana-replace-ethereum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/solana/will-solana-replace-ethereum/</guid><description>Ethereum is a marketplace technology that provides a means to send and receive cryptocurrency, access investments and financial services. It’s an innovative blockchain that’s programmable and provides the foundation for applications, games, and other services.
While ETH or Ethereum is one of the most prominent open-source blockchains globally, Solana is a quickly emerging option that may exceed Ethereum. ETH allowed investors to access financial contracts involving lending, borrowing, and earning interest on crypto investments while bypassing the banking system altogether.</description></item></channel></rss>