<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Decentralized Finance (Defi) on</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/docs/defi/</link><description>Recent content in Decentralized Finance (Defi) on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://solanaguide.github.io/docs/defi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Liquidity Pools - Solana Defi Guide</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/defi/liquidity-pools-solana-defi-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/defi/liquidity-pools-solana-defi-guide/</guid><description>Liquidity Pools in DeFi A liquidity pool (LP) is another structure that powers decentralized finance, allowing users to enjoy all the services they provide. Before we define what liquidity pools are, we must understand what liquidity means.
Simply put, liquidity refers to how easy it is to convert an asset (like cryptocurrency) from one form to another (say fiat currency) without sacrificing its market value. In the crypto space, liquidity describes how easy it is to swap one crypto asset for another.</description></item><item><title>Token Swaps &amp; Trading On Decentralized Exchanges (DEX)</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/defi/token-swaps-trading-on-decentralized-exchanges-dex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/defi/token-swaps-trading-on-decentralized-exchanges-dex/</guid><description>What Is Swapping? Swapping is a popular tool in the Solana decentralized finance industry. Swapping allows investors to substitute their Solana asset for another without necessarily adding new frameworks, support structures, or code.
The process involves exchanging Solana for another asset, say Ethereum or Bitcoin, on a one-on-one ratio. This can involve swaps between Solana and stablecoins such as USDC and USDT, or any one of the hundreds of tokens that exist within the Solana ecosystem thanks to Solana&amp;rsquo;s SPL token program.</description></item><item><title>Yield &amp; Liquidity Farming For Passive Income - Solana Defi Guide</title><link>https://solanaguide.github.io/defi/yield-liquidity-farming-for-passive-income-solana-defi-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solanaguide.github.io/defi/yield-liquidity-farming-for-passive-income-solana-defi-guide/</guid><description>Yield Farming Yield farming is one of the trending ideas in the decentralized finance (DeFi) realm. Since last year, it has overtaken the crypto ecosystem, mainly because it compensates investors for securing their cryptocurrency assets in the DeFi market.
What Is Yield Farming? Yield farming is a process that involves lending or staking crypto assets to generate rewards or high returns as passive incomes in the form of additional cryptocurrency. In simpler terms, yield farming is a DeFi activity that allows you to make more cryptocurrencies with your digital assets.</description></item></channel></rss>